Eufrat Tsaqib Qasthari

+62 85155070615, eutsat@gmail.com Menteng, Central Jakarta, 10310

Summary

Eufrat currently works on AI/ML at LinkAja and also organizing CNCF community groups in Indonesia. He experienced in applying AI, IoT and cloud technologies on production systems. In spare time, he enjoys road cycling and tinkering. He speaks in English and Indonesian.

Experiences

Senior AI/ML Engineer, LinkAja (May 2020-Present)

Leading digital financial service from the largest SOEs (BUMN) in Indonesia, including four state-owned banks (Mandiri, BNI, BRI and BTN), national telco (Telkomsel) and national oil & gas company (Pertamina). Go-to person for all AI/ML production systems.

Develop AI/ML infrastructure and platform with Python, TensorFlow, PyTorch, Kubeflow, Kubernetes, GPUs, etc. Develop AI/ML services for eKYC, chatbot, customer segmentation, fraud detection and credit scoring for 60+ million users across Indonesia with 8+ million inference monthly.

Co-founder, Replus (June 2019-May 2020)

Technical Lead & Co-founder, Replus (June 2017-May 2019)

Made a small company while still in college (PT), supported with 690M IDR (equivalent to 50K USD) from multiple competitions and sponsors including DIB UI, Ministry of Research and Technology, Astra International, DIGITARAYA and Google Cloud. Lead software engineering team to develop an app for energy management IoT devices with JavaScript, Polymer, MQTT, Google Cloud etc.

Software Engineer, Nodeflux (December 2018-May 2020)

Hired before graduation. Largest computer vision AI company in Indonesia (NVIDIA Partner and ranked 25th in NIST FRVT). Develop a core cloud platform for deep learning analytics using Go, Python, Kubernetes, GPUs, gRPC etc. with the entire API documentation site. Develop eKYC API for identifying 150+ million Indonesian identities and COVID-19 public mobility monitoring system on top of 2600+ CCTVs.

Software Engineer Intern, Nodeflux (July 2018-August 2018)

Best Intern. Benchmark object-detection systems with JavaScript, Python, Multiple MQ systems, ELK stack, and Websocket. Benchmark video streaming protocols and decoders with RTSP, HLS etc.

Education

University of Indonesia, Bachelor of Science (August 2019)

Physics Major, System and Instrumentation Minor.

Research on Hyperspectral Computer Vision at Bio-Imaging Physics Research Group (initiating DNN usage for hyperspectral imagery).

Chief Programmer KRAI (ABU ROBOCON) Division at University Robotics Team.

Skills

Programming Languages: Python, Go, JavaScript and C

Tools: Git, Kubernetes, TensorFlow, PyTorch, GPUs, MQ, Google Cloud and AWS

Awards

PPBT Startup Funding 2018, Selected National

NYALA Smart Energy Hackathon 2018, 2nd National

App Innovation Challenge Compfest 9, Finalist National

Selected PKM-GT RISTEKDIKTI, National Nominee

KRAI (ABU ROBOCON) Robotics Competition, 2nd Regional 2 Level